<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-22T14:26:03-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">studio3_repo</title><subtitle>The &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyde.getpoole.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; theme for &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, refreshed.</subtitle><author><name>Andrew Fong</name></author><entry><title type="html">Joanna’s Studio3 Repo2_OKRs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/hello-hydeout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joanna’s Studio3 Repo2_OKRs" /><published>2020-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/hello-hydeout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/hello-hydeout.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dream-scenario-of-this-project&quot;&gt;The Dream Scenario of this project:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Establishing a platform, probably a website, organizing different categories of graphics into topics and clearly demonstrate the trends/ outliers of datasets collected and analyzed by the data company, AppliedXL. Everyone gets the chance to watch the site, but they will need to subscribe to platform for getting the overall datasets. The platform also collects viewers’ feedbacks on data interpretations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dream scenario is getting this platform &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subscribed&lt;/code&gt; by as much newsrooms or freelance journalists as possible or getting as much &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;contribution lines&lt;/code&gt; on media outlets (“i.e. Data gathered and analyzed by AppliedXL”) as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the product’s engineering perspective, the dream scenario is being able to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;automate&lt;/code&gt; most of the data piplines and the production of graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-to---dos&quot;&gt;Some TO - DOs:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Data sourcing with computational journalism mindsets.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Information processing with mathematical, statician focuses. Will get helps from the data scientists on the team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Demonstrating of data findings as graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 1px solid rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;https://www.figma.com/embed?embed_host=share&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.figma.com%2Ffile%2F7seE31TNKfayS4fDnCOuja%2FUntitled%3Fnode-id%3D0%253A1&amp;amp;chrome=DOCUMENTATION&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gathering feedbacks and knowledge from the journalists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Fong</name></author><summary type="html">The Dream Scenario of this project: Establishing a platform, probably a website, organizing different categories of graphics into topics and clearly demonstrate the trends/ outliers of datasets collected and analyzed by the data company, AppliedXL. Everyone gets the chance to watch the site, but they will need to subscribe to platform for getting the overall datasets. The platform also collects viewers’ feedbacks on data interpretations. The dream scenario is getting this platform subscribed by as much newsrooms or freelance journalists as possible or getting as much contribution lines on media outlets (“i.e. Data gathered and analyzed by AppliedXL”) as possible. For the product’s engineering perspective, the dream scenario is being able to automate most of the data piplines and the production of graphics. Some TO - DOs: Data sourcing with computational journalism mindsets. Information processing with mathematical, statician focuses. Will get helps from the data scientists on the team. Demonstrating of data findings as graphics. Gathering feedbacks and knowledge from the journalists.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Joanna’s Studio3 Repo1_Starting point</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/hello-hydeout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Joanna’s Studio3 Repo1_Starting point" /><published>2020-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/hello-hydeout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/hello-hydeout.html">&lt;p&gt;I am a Data tracker enthusiast long before COVID. I got the chance to work on it, and I interviewed some data journalists/ data editors in newsrooms. I found some problems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-problem-you-plan-to-address&quot;&gt;What is the problem you plan to address?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to build affordable data trackers as news products with testing and iterations which collect feedback from the audience? Breaking down the problem into three categories:
The needs: Newsrooms wants to leverage their reporting by building long-term data trackers which monitor trends and spot outliers. This has already been proven by news coverage during the COVID, like nearly every media built some sort of data tracker.
The gaps: Newsrooms may not have the capability of building data trackers. Even if they have the capability, maintaining a tracker needs a huge amount of efforts.
The risks: Data trackers always need intensive collaboration within engineers, journalists, editors, graphic designers… meaning that the production timeline is relatively longer than average stories, in this way, the story might be no longer newsy. Also, the data pipeline is hard to rebuild or waste a lot of time if the news product is getting audience’s feedback after it’s fully published online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-the-project-look-like-in-your-current-vision-of-it&quot;&gt;What does the project look like in your current vision of it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Stories as Prototypes]:
Data stories would serve as prototypes for the more advanced data tracker news products &amp;lt;- test out the workflow of building data trackers as news products based on iterations of designing news stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;updated-on-sep-21&quot;&gt;updated on Sep 21:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the talk with my media partner, AppliedXL, I recalibrarted the project to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[Bridgeting Data and Journalists]&lt;/code&gt;, which trys to figure out how to connect data journalists/ investigative reporters with organized real-time/ up-to-date datasets, and to collect their feedbacks and insights or to ask them giving us feedbacks and insights by conducting interviews for improving the analysis of datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;at-this-stage-what-do-you-think-the-final-product-or-deliverable-will-be&quot;&gt;At this stage, what do you think the final product or deliverable will be?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several experiments involving data stories and its advanced data tracker news products. What I have experimented so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A. COVID-related clinical trial studies data analysis story as the prototype for the TrialXLl data tracker/ dashboard&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;B. US-listed Chinese companies filling record data analysis story as the prototype for a potential US-listed Chinese companies tracker&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C. COVID mask order/ stay at home order/ reopening order data analysis story as the prototype for a potential feature improvement of the CovidXL tracker&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Andrew Fong</name></author><summary type="html">I am a Data tracker enthusiast long before COVID. I got the chance to work on it, and I interviewed some data journalists/ data editors in newsrooms. I found some problems: What is the problem you plan to address? How to build affordable data trackers as news products with testing and iterations which collect feedback from the audience? Breaking down the problem into three categories: The needs: Newsrooms wants to leverage their reporting by building long-term data trackers which monitor trends and spot outliers. This has already been proven by news coverage during the COVID, like nearly every media built some sort of data tracker. The gaps: Newsrooms may not have the capability of building data trackers. Even if they have the capability, maintaining a tracker needs a huge amount of efforts. The risks: Data trackers always need intensive collaboration within engineers, journalists, editors, graphic designers… meaning that the production timeline is relatively longer than average stories, in this way, the story might be no longer newsy. Also, the data pipeline is hard to rebuild or waste a lot of time if the news product is getting audience’s feedback after it’s fully published online. What does the project look like in your current vision of it? [Stories as Prototypes]: Data stories would serve as prototypes for the more advanced data tracker news products &amp;lt;- test out the workflow of building data trackers as news products based on iterations of designing news stories. updated on Sep 21: After the talk with my media partner, AppliedXL, I recalibrarted the project to [Bridgeting Data and Journalists], which trys to figure out how to connect data journalists/ investigative reporters with organized real-time/ up-to-date datasets, and to collect their feedbacks and insights or to ask them giving us feedbacks and insights by conducting interviews for improving the analysis of datasets. At this stage, what do you think the final product or deliverable will be? Several experiments involving data stories and its advanced data tracker news products. What I have experimented so far: A. COVID-related clinical trial studies data analysis story as the prototype for the TrialXLl data tracker/ dashboard B. US-listed Chinese companies filling record data analysis story as the prototype for a potential US-listed Chinese companies tracker C. COVID mask order/ stay at home order/ reopening order data analysis story as the prototype for a potential feature improvement of the CovidXL tracker</summary></entry></feed>